A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1959
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1959
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.641-I
This collection consists of 11,400 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library on 5 August 1964.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
There are also architectural drawings of the West Grounds Site Plan, Engineering Building, and New Roads and three sheets of drawings for Proposed Changes in the North Approach to the Rotunda.
Contents List
- General Files, 1959
  - "A - Am" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 1)
  - "An - Az" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 1)
  - Admissions 1959 (Box 1)
  - Air Force 1959 (Box 1)
  - Airport 1959 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Association 1959 (Box 1)
  - Alumni - Atlanta Chapter 1959 (Box 1)
  - Alumni - Charleston, West Virginia Chapter 1959 (Box 1)
  - Alumni - Long Island Chapter 1959 (Box 1)
  - Alumni - Memphis Chapter 1959 (Box 1)
  - Alumni - New York Chapter 1959 (Box 1)
  - Alumni - Norfolk Chapter 1959 (Box 1)
  - Alumni - Peninsula Chapter (folder empty) 1959 (Box 1)
  - Alumni - Roanoke Chapter 1959 (Box 1)
  - Alumni - Philadelphia (folder empty) 1959 (Box 1)
  - Alumni - Staunton Chapter (folder empty) 1959 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Board of Trustees (folder empty) 1959 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Fund 1959 (Box 1)
  - American Association of Land-Grant Colleges and Universities 1959 (Box 1)
  - American Association of University Professors 1959 (Box 1)
  - American Council on Education 1959 (Box 1)
  - American Field Service (folder empty) 1959 (Box 1)
  - Annual Reports 1959 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "A" (folder empty) 1959 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "B" 1959 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "C" 1959 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "D" 1959 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "E" (folder empty) 1959 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "F" 1959 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "G" 1959 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "H" 1959 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "I" 1959 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "J" (folder empty) 1959 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "K" 1959 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "L" 1959 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "M" (folder empty) 1959 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "N" (folder empty) 1959 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "O" (folder empty) 1959 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "P" 1959 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "Q" (folder empty) 1959 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "R" 1959 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "S" 1959 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "T" 1959 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "U" (folder empty) 1959 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "V" (folder empty) 1959 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "W" 1959 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "X - Y - Z" (folder empty) 1959 (Box 2)
  - Architecture 1959 (Box 2)
  - Army - General 1959 (Box 2)
  - Army - ROTC 1959 (Box 2)
  - Army - Judge Advocate General's (J.A.G.) School 1959 (Box 2)
  - Art 1959 (Box 2)
  - Art Commission 1959 (Box 2)
  - Association of American Colleges 1959 (Box 2)
  - Association of American Universities 1959 (Box 2)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges 1959 (Box 2)
  - Astronomy 1959 (Box 2)
  - Athletics - Atlantic Coast Conference (ACC) 1959 (Box 2)
  - Athletics - General 1959 (Box 2)
  - Athletics - NCAA 1959 (Box 2)
  - Athletics - Football: Clemson Game, 26 September 1959 1959 (Box 2)
  - Athletics - Football: Vanderbilt Game, 24 October 1959 1959 (Box 2)
  - Athletics - Football: William and Mary Game, 19 September 1959 1959 (Box 2)
  - Athletics - Football: University of South Carolina Game, 7 November 1959 (Commonwealth Day) 1959 (Box 2)
  - Attorney General 1959 (Box 2)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts 1959 (Box 2)
  - "Ba - Bl" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 3)
  - "Bm - Bz" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 3)
  - Biology 1959 (Box 3)
  - Biology - Mountain Lake 1959 (Box 3)
  - Bibliographic Society 1959 (Box 3)
  - Blandy Farm 1959 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds 1959 (Box 3)
  - Building Program 1959 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - Architects and Engineers 1959 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - Clinch Valley College, January - June 1959 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - Clinch Valley College, July - December 1959 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - Engineering Buildings 1959 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - Field House 1959 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - George Mason College 1959 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - Life Science Building (folder empty) 1959 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - Medical Buildings 1959 (Box 3)
  - Bureau of Population and Economic Research 1959 (Box 3)
  - Bursar 1959 (Box 3)
  - Business Administration, Graduate School - January - June 1959 (Box 4)
  - Business Administration, Graduate School - July - December 1959 (Box 4)
  - Byrd, Senator Harry F. 1959 (Box 4)
  - "Ca - Ck" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 4)
  - "Cl - Cz" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 4)
  - Cabell Portrait 1959 (Box 4)
  - Cavalier Daily 1959 (Box 4)
  - Chemistry 1959 (Box 4)
  - Classics 1959 (Box 4)
  - Clinch Valley College 1959 (Box 4)
  - Clippings 1959 (Box 4)
  - College of Arts and Sciences - January - June 1959 (Box 5)
  - College of Arts and Sciences - July - December (includes LS, Shannon to Duren, re: admission of black students to the College) 1959 (Box 5)
  - Commerce, McIntire Undergraduate School 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Academic Costume 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Academic Policy 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Accessions 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Administrative 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Algernon Sydney Sullivan Award 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Arboretum Advisory 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Art Museum 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Athletic 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Balch Estate (folder empty) 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Biology Advisory 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Blandy Farm Board 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Board 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Business Administration, Graduate School (folder empty) 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Calendar 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Catalogue 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Cemetery (folder empty) 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Cemetery 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Chapel 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Clinch Valley College Advisory 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Clinch Valley College Building (folder empty) 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - College Costs (folder empty) 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - College and Education (folder empty) 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Graduate and Education (folder empty) 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Commons Building Name 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Computation Center 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Counselors' (see Dormitory Counselors Committee) 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Contractual Relations (folder empty) 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Dormitory Counselors' 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Engineering Advisory 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Extension 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Extension Program in the State 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Fellowships Awards (folder empty) 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Field House 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Fire Protection 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Fraternity 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Fulbright Awards 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Graduate 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Hospital Architecture Advisory (folder empty) 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Inauguration of President 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Institute for Research in the Social Sciences Council 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Lecturers - Page-Barbour and J. W. Richard 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Lecturers - Special (folder empty) 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Library (folder empty) 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Life Science Building Plan 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Mary Washington College (folder empty) 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Medical Board of the Hospital (folder empty) 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Memorial, World War II 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Miscellaneous (folder empty) 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Mountain Lake Biology Station 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Naval ROTC Selection (folder empty) 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Nuclear Advisory (folder empty) 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Old Dominion Foundation Grant 1959 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Orientation 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Patents 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Planning 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Power Plant (folder empty) 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - President's Council (folder empty) 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Processions 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Public Occasions 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Public Relations 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Research 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Research in the Social Sciences (folder empty) 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Retirement 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Rushton Seminars (folder empty) 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Schedule and Classroom Assignments 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Scholarships, Loans, and Employment 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Rhodes Scholarship 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Student Activities 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Student Counseling (folder empty) 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Student Financial Aid 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Student Health (folder empty) 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Student Union 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Summer Session 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Summer Session - Undergraduate Degrees 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Summer Session - Graduate Degrees 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Tenth Annual Forum on Finance 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Traffic Control 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Tree (folder empty) 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - University Undergraduates 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - University Area Center Research Council (folder empty) 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Virginia Status of U.Va. Students 1959 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Virginia Quarterly Review 1959 (Box 6)
  - Commission on Constitutional Government 1959 (Box 6)
  - Comptroller 1959 (Box 6)
  - Computation Center 1959 (Box 6)
  - Confidential Reports 1959 (Box 6)
  - Cooper, Weldon 1959 (Box 6)
  - Council of Southern Universities (folder empty) 1959 (Box 6)
  - "D" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 6)
  - Darden, Colgate W. 1959 (Box 6)
  - "E" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 6)
  - Economics 1959 (Box 6)
  - Education 1959 (Box 6)
  - Endowment Fund 1959 (Box 7)
  - Endowment Fund (Contingent Fund) 1959 (Box 7)
  - Engineering 1959 (Box 7)
  - English 1959 (Box 7)
  - Enrollment (folder empty) 1959 (Box 7)
  - Extension Division - January - June 1959 (Box 7)
  - Extension Division - July - December 1959 (Box 7)
  - Extension Division - Northern Virginia Branch (see George Mason College of Virginia) 1959 (Box 7)
  - Extension Division - Richmond Branch (folder empty) 1959 (Box 7)
  - Extension Division - Southwest Virginia 1959 (Box 7)
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 7)
  - Faculty 1959 (Box 7)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships 1959 (Box 8)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Rhodes 1959 (Box 8)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Ford Foundation 1959 (Box 8)
  - Foreign Affairs 1959 (Box 8)
  - Finals 1959 (Box 8)
  - Food Service 1959 (Box 8)
  - Forestry 1959 (Box 8)
  - Founder's Day 1959 (Box 8)
  - Fraternities 1959 (Box 8)
  - Fulbright Fellowships 1959 (Box 8)
  - Fund for Adult Education 1959 (Box 8)
  - "G" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 8)
  - General Assembly (see Political File) 1959 (Box 8)
  - Geography 1959 (Box 8)
  - Geology 1959 (Box 8)
  - Germanic Languages and Russian 1959 (Box 8)
  - Gifts and Grants 1959 (Box 8)
  - Governor's Office 1959 (Box 8)
  - Governor's Office - Advices of Allotment 1959 (Box 8)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences 1959 (Box 8)
  - "Ha - Hk" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 9)
  - "Hm - Hz" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 9)
  - Highway Department 1959 (Box 9)
  - Hildreth, W. S. 1959 (Box 9)
  - History 1959 (Box 9)
  - History - Madison Papers 1959 (Box 9)
  - Honors Courses 1959 (Box 9)
  - Honor System 1959 (Box 9)
  - Hospital: January - June 1959 (Box 9)
  - Hospital: July - December 1959 (Box 9)
  - Hospital: Medical Board 1959 (Box 9)
  - Hospital: Statistical Reports 1959 (Box 9)
  - Housing (see University Houses) 1959 (Box 9)
  - Hull Foundation 1959 (Box 9)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 9)
  - Inauguration 1959 (Box 9)
  - Institute for Research in the Social Sciences 1959 (Box 9)
  - Institute of International Education 1959 (Box 9)
  - Insurance 1959 (Box 9)
  - International Association of Universities 1959 (Box 9)
  - Invitations - Not Accepted 1959 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "A" 1959 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "B" 1959 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "C" 1959 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "D" 1959 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "E" 1959 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "F" 1959 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "G" 1959 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "H" 1959 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "I" 1959 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "J" 1959 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "K" 1959 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "L" 1959 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "M" 1959 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "N" 1959 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "O" 1959 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "P" 1959 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "Q" (folder empty) 1959 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "R" 1959 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "S" 1959 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "T" 1959 (Box 11)
  - Invitations - "U" 1959 (Box 11)
  - Invitations - "V" 1959 (Box 11)
  - Invitations - "W" 1959 (Box 11)
  - Invitations - "X - Y - Z" 1959 (Box 11)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 11)
  - Jefferson, Thomas - Center (see Economics) 1959 (Box 11)
  - Jefferson, Thomas - Memorial Foundation 1959 (Box 11)
  - Jefferson, Thomas - Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 11)
  - Jefferson Society 1959 (Box 11)
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 11)
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 11)
  - Law School 1959 (Box 11)
  - Lectures - General 1959 (Box 12)
  - Lectures - Page-Barbour 1959 (Box 12)
  - Lectures - Richard 1959 (Box 12)
  - Legal Matters 1959 (Box 12)
  - Legislative Program 1959 (Box 12)
  - Library 1959 (Box 12)
  - Library - Board of Alderman 1959 (Box 12)
  - Loan Funds 1959 (Box 12)
  - "Ma - Me" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 12)
  - "Mc" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 12)
  - McConnell Award 1959 (Box 12)
  - "Mi - Mz" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 12)
  - Madison Hall 1959 (Box 13)
  - Mary Washington College - Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 13)
  - Mary Washington College - Dr. Simpson, Chancellor 1959 (Box 13)
  - Mary Washington College - Mr. Woodward 1959 (Box 13)
  - Mathematics 1959 (Box 13)
  - Maxwell Air Force Base 1959 (Box 13)
  - Medicine 1959 (Box 13)
  - Music 1959 (Box 13)
  - "N" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 13)
  - National Association of State Universities 1959 (Box 13)
  - National Science Foundation 1959 (Box 13)
  - Naval ROTC 1959 (Box 13)
  - Navy - General 1959 (Box 13)
  - Newcomb Hall 1959 (Box 13)
  - News Letter 1959 (Box 13)
  - Nursing School 1959 (Box 13)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 13)
  - Oak Ridge 1959 (Box 13)
  - "Pa - Pe" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 14)
  - "Pf - Pz" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 14)
  - Pending 1959 (Box 14)
  - Personnel 1959 (Box 14)
  - Phi Beta Kappa 1959 (Box 14)
  - Philosophy 1959 (Box 14)
  - Photographs 1959 (Box 14)
  - Physics 1959 (Box 14)
  - Political File (see General Assembly) 1959 (Box 14)
  - Political Science 1959 (Box 14)
  - Possible Donors 1959 (Box 14)
  - Pratt, John Lee Trace Analysis Laboratory (see Chemistry) 1959 (Box 14)
  - President's Council 1959 (Box 14)
  - Provost 1959 (Box 14)
  - Psychology 1959 (Box 14)
  - Public Occasions (folder empty) 1959 (Box 14)
  - Purchasing 1959 (Box 14)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 14)
  - Questionnaires 1959 (Box 14)
  - "R" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 14)
  - Radio 1959 (Box 14)
  - Raven Society 1959 (Box 14)
  - Recommendations 1959 (Box 14)
  - Regional Education 1959 (Box 15)
  - Religion 1959 (Box 15)
  - Remington Rand 1959 (Box 15)
  - Registrar 1959 (Box 15)
  - Requisitions 1959 (Box 15)
  - Research 1959 (Box 15)
  - Romance Languages 1959 (Box 15)
  - Rural Social Economics 1959 (Box 15)
  - "Sa - Sl" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 15)
  - "Sm - Sl" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 15)
  - Segregation 1959 (Box 15)
  - Senate 1959 (Box 15)
  - Seven Society 1959 (Box 15)
  - President's Reception (Shannon - Social) 1959 (Box 16)
  - Sigma Xi 1959 (Box 16)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools 1959 (Box 16)
  - Southern Association of Land-Grant Colleges 1959 (Box 16)
  - Southern Association of Science and Industry 1959 (Box 16)
  - Southern Regional Education Board (see Regional Education) 1959 (Box 16)
  - Sociology 1959 (Box 16)
  - Southern University Conference 1959 (Box 16)
  - Speech and Drama 1959 (Box 16)
  - State Board of Education 1959 (Box 16)
  - Student Health Department 1959 (Box 16)
  - Summer Session 1959 (Box 16)
  - "T" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 17)
  - Travel 1959 (Box 17)
  - Treasurer of Virginia 1959 (Box 17)
  - "U" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 17)
  - United Nations 1959 (Box 17)
  - U. S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare 1959 (Box 17)
  - U. S. Department of State 1959 (Box 17)
  - University Center in Virginia 1959 (Box 17)
  - University Houses 1959 (Box 17)
  - University News Service (see Information Service) 1959 (Box 17)
  - University Press 1959 (Box 17)
  - University of Virginia Weekly Bulletin 1959 (Box 17)
  - "V" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 17)
  - Virginia Academy of Science 1959 (Box 17)
  - Virginia Education Association 1959 (Box 17)
  - Virginia Junior Academy of Science 1959 (Box 17)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1959 (Box 17)
  - Virginia Status of University Students Committee 1959 (Box 17)
  - Visitors - Dockets and Minutes, 1959 1959 (Box 18)
  - Visitors - General: January - June 1959 (Box 18)
  - Visitors - General: July - December 1959 (Box 18)
  - Visitors - Berkeley, Mr. Norborne 1959 (Box 18)
  - Visitors - Blanton, Mr. T. H. 1959 (Box 18)
  - Visitors - Bryan, Judge A. V. 1959 (Box 18)
  - Visitors - Coxe, Mr. Whitwell W. 1959 (Box 18)
  - Visitors - Fenwick, Mr. C. R. 1959 (Box 18)
  - Visitors - Greear, Mr. F. B. 1959 (Box 18)
  - Visitors - Hartfield, Mr. Joseph 1959 (Box 18)
  - Visitors - Jones, Mrs. B. T. 1959 (Box 18)
  - Visitors - Lantor, Mrs. Nathan 1959 (Box 18)
  - Visitors - McWane, Mr. Henry 1959 (Box 18)
  - Visitors - Martin, Dr. Walter B. 1959 (Box 18)
  - Visitors - Montague, Mr. E. S. 1959 (Box 18)
  - Visitors - Paschall, Mr. Davis Y. 1959 (Box 18)
  - Visitors - Pollock, Mr. Herbert 1959 (Box 18)
  - "Wa - Wh" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 19)
  - "Wi - Wz" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 19)
  - Washington Center for Metropolitan Studies 1959 (Box 19)
  - Wilson, Woodrow 1959 (Box 19)
  - Women, Dean of 1959 (Box 19)
  - Wright Patterson Air Force Base (Annual College Representatives Conference) 1959 (Box 19)
  - "X - Y - Z" Miscellaneous 1959 (Box 19)
  - 541 I II
  - SUB-SERIES I: General Files, 1943-1944 (Box 1-12)
  - SUB-SERIES II: General Files, 1945 (Box 13-21)
  - SUB-SERIES I: General Files, 1943-1944
  - "A" Miscellaneous 1943-1944 (Box 1)
  - Aeronautics 1943-1944 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Board--Class Managers 1943-1944 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Board--General Correspondence 1943-1944 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Board--Office 1943-1944 (Box 1)
  - American Council on Education 1943-1944 (Box 1)
  - Ancient Languages 1943-1944 (Box 1)
  - Annual Reports 1943-1944 (Box 1)
  - Applications for Positions 1943-1944 (Box 1)
  - Architects and Engineers 1943-1944 (Box 1)
  - Art and Architecture 1943-1944 (Box 1)
  - Art Commission--Bolivar Portrait; Alderman Bust--Keck 1943-1944 (Box 1-a)
  - Association of American Colleges 1943-1944 (Box 1-a)
  - Astronomy 1943-1944 (Box 1-a)
  - Athletics 1943-1944 (Box 1-a)
  - "B" Miscellaneous 1943-1944 (Box 1-a)
  - Biology 1943-1944 (Box 1-a)
  - Biology--Blandy Farm--contains monthly reports 1943-1944 (Box 1-a)
  - Biology--Mountain Lake 1943-1944 (Box 1-a)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Cafeteria and Dining Hall--Commons 1943-1944 (Box 1-a)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Several 1943 (Box 1-a)
  - Building Program--(general sites of future buildings discussed) 1943-1944 (Box 1-a)
  - Building Program--Nurses Home 1943-1944 (Box 2)
  - Building Program--Site Plan 1943-1944 (Box 2)
  - Bursar's Office 1943-1944 (Box 2)
  - "C" Miscellaneous 1943-1944 (Box 2)
  - Carnegie Corporation 1943-1944 (Box 2)
  - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching 1943-1944 (Box 2)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace 1943-1944 (Box 2)
  - Catalogues 1943-1944 (Box 2)
  - Chemistry 1943-1944 (Box 2)
  - Cocke's Biography 1943-1944 (Box 2)
  - Church Society for College Work 1943-1944 (Box 2)
  - Committees 1943-1944 (Box 2)
  - Committee--(emergency) Displaced Foreign Students 1943-1944 (Box 2)
  - Committee--Local Building 1943-1944 (Box 2)
  - Committee--New Buildings 1943-1944 (Box 2)
  - Committee--on Non-Virginia Fees 1943-1944 (Box 2)
  - Commons (includes correspondence with the Navy concerning use of commons) 1943-1944 (Box 3)
  - "D" Miscellaneous 1943-1944 (Box 3)
  - Dean Ferguson (correspondence re--curriculum reorganization and the acceleration of programs) 1943-1944 (Box 3)
  - Dean Finley 1943-1944 (Box 3)
  - Dean Lewis (information re--V-12 program, repayment of Honor Loan Fund, reopening of fraternities with new rules--concerning women, absences from class, rushing, and appointment of policemen and night-watchmen) 1943-1944 (Box 3)
  - "E" Miscellaneous 1943-1944 (Box 3)
  - Economics 1943-1944 (Box 3)
  - Education--General 1943-1944 (Box 3)
  - Education--Graduate 1943-1944 (Box 3)
  - Education--Nursing 1943-1944 (Box 3)
  - Endowment--including Alumni Board of Trustees Records 1943-1944 (Box 3)
  - Engineering 1943-1944 (Box 4)
  - English 1943-1944 (Box 4)
  - Extension Division--General (P.O.W. correspondence school program; history of the extension division) 1943-1944 (Box 4)
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1943-1944 (Box 4)
  - Faculty 1943-1944 (Box 4)
  - Faculty--Instructors and Assistants 1943-1944 (Box 4)
  - Fellowships and Endowments--William A. Smith Memorial 1943-1944 (Box 4)
  - Finals (2 folders) 1943-1944 (Box 4)
  - Foreign Affairs 1943-1944 (Box 4)
  - Forestry 1943-1944 (Box 4)
  - Forestry (Seward Forest) 1943-1944 (Box 4)
  - Founder's Day--speech--"Thomas Jefferson--in Memoriam," by C. A. Beard; portrait of Simon Bolivar presented 1943-1944 (Box 5)
  - "G" Miscellaneous (Wilson Gee summarizes his ideas concerning the service of the U. of VA to the State of Virginia) 1943-1944 (Box 5)
  - General Education Board 1943-1944 (Box 5)
  - Geology 1943-1944 (Box 5)
  - Geological Survey 1943-1944 (Box 5)
  - Germanic Languages 1943-1944 (Box 5)
  - Gifts to the University 1943-1944 (Box 5)
  - Governor's Office (2 folders) 1943-1944 (Box 5)
  - "H" Miscellaneous 1943-1944 (Box 5)
  - History--Corcoran School of 1943-1944 (Box 5)
  - Honor System (receives $10,000 bequest from a student who had been expelled) 1943-1944 (Box 5)
  - Honors Courses 1943-1944 (Box 5)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1943-1944 (Box 5)
  - Insurance--TIAA, Travelers 1943-1944 (Box 5)
  - International Cooperative Commission 1943-1944 (Box 5)
  - Invitations 1943-1944 (Box 6)
  - Institute of Public Affairs--Revival 1943-1944 (Box 6)
  - Institute of International Education 1943-1944 (Box 6)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1943-1944 (Box 6)
  - Jefferson Memorial Foundation 1943-1944 (Box 6)